<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Suraj Yadav</title><link>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Suraj Yadav</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My mobile/tablets until now</title><link>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/my-mobile/tablets-until-now/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/my-mobile/tablets-until-now/</guid><description>My mobile phones until now 🔗I have timestamped them with my school grades because I don&amp;rsquo;t remember exact years.
Nokia 3310c 🔗 5th - 7th grade Credit - https://archiwum.allegro.pl/oferta/nokia-3310c-plus-i7246256743.html
My first ever personal phone. It was Java based. I rocked this for about 2 years. I played so many games on this thing. Some of the ones I can recall is Spiderman, Street fighter ripoffs, Tomb raider. And ofc bounce.</description></item><item><title>My list of Emacs packages</title><link>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/my-list-of-emacs-packages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/my-list-of-emacs-packages/</guid><description>My list of Emacs packages 🔗magit 🔗The best git interface I&amp;rsquo;ve ever used. I cannot imagine using anything else but this for git.
which-key 🔗Shows completion keybinds for incomplete keys. Gets you familiar with modes.
ivy + ivy-rich 🔗Completion engine for emacs. Comes with rich observability features like
Entities(command, function, variable&amp;hellip;) docstring Keybind of commands and much more features to make using the minibuffer easy.
golden-ratio 🔗Automatically expands the window you switch to.</description></item><item><title>What motivates me (I think)</title><link>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/what-motivates-me-i-think/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/what-motivates-me-i-think/</guid><description>What motivates me (I think) 🔗2 things
Variety Speed Variety 🔗I have noticed about myself that I like heterogeneity whether it comes to programming or food or games. They are like flavours I want to try and I want to try all of them. It helps me grow as an individual. Its the same reason why I tried Object oriented programming when I was a hardcore functional programmer, why I mix my food unevenly so that every bite will taste different and why I explore every part of the game so that I don&amp;rsquo;t miss out on an experience.</description></item><item><title>Why I made a public diary</title><link>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/why-i-made-a-public-diary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/why-i-made-a-public-diary/</guid><description>Why I made a public diary 🔗I have kept things to myself all my life, because I found it hard to open up to people. And that did not help. Communication is what makes us humans(probably).
I have defintely matured to open up. Now, I try to be an open book. I want people to see me as me. I want them to know where I come from.
This diary will be my own corner.</description></item><item><title>Sweet CICD for my Portfolio</title><link>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/sweet-cicd-for-my-portfolio/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/sweet-cicd-for-my-portfolio/</guid><description>Sweet CICD for my Portfolio 🔗What my current setup is? 🔗My portfolio is hosted on Github pages. Github pages has support for selecting the directory to host. The options are &amp;ldquo;root&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;/docs&amp;rdquo; directories.
I build my portfolio locally in &amp;ldquo;/docs&amp;rdquo; directory and push it. I chose &amp;ldquo;/docs&amp;rdquo; to host in Github pages on master branch.
This setup is a bit tedious. There are 2 problems.
The build is in master repo I have to track the build in git What I want?</description></item><item><title>A bit about Consistency</title><link>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/a-bit-about-consistency/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/a-bit-about-consistency/</guid><description>A bit about Consistency 🔗I have decided I wanna get good at Digital Art. Art is hard, it&amp;rsquo;s tough work. I want to integrate it in my life and make it second nature. I want to miss it when I am not drawing.
There&amp;rsquo;s no secret recipe to it, but brutal consistency. And so, I have decided to draw a lot of bosoms. This piece is a promise to myself.</description></item><item><title>A game which I will make(someday)</title><link>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/a-game-which-i-will-makesomeday/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/a-game-which-i-will-makesomeday/</guid><description>A game which I will make(someday) 🔗Motivation 🔗I have been playing alot of Oracle in Dota. I like the fact that he&amp;rsquo;s a double edged sword. The spell combos feel like a mini game itself and I think I can make a game out of it.
Gameplay loop 🔗For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know Oracle&amp;rsquo;s spells, heres a quick introduction
Fortune&amp;rsquo;s End 🔗A channeled ability which roots the enemy. Can be casted on enemy or ally.</description></item><item><title>Desi Literate Programming in Bhailang</title><link>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/desi-literate-programming-in-bhailang/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/desi-literate-programming-in-bhailang/</guid><description>Desi Literate Programming in Bhailang 🔗What is Bhailang1? 🔗According to its landing page, &amp;ldquo;A toy programming language written in Typescript&amp;rdquo;. Its a programming language based on Indian slangs, which makes it fun &amp;amp; accessible for anyone who knows Hindi.
What is Literate Programming2? 🔗According to Donald Knuth, the creator of Literate programming, &amp;ldquo;Literate programming is a programming methodology that combines a programming language with a documentation language, making programs more robust, more portable, and more easily maintained than programs written only in a high-level language.</description></item><item><title>Your best friends in Emacs</title><link>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/your-best-friends-in-emacs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/your-best-friends-in-emacs/</guid><description>Your best friends in Emacs 🔗In emacs, You are either 🔗 Invoking a function through a key press Invoking a function manually Describe Mode1 C-h m 🔗Describe mode gives you a list of all enabled Minor modes, functions in the major mode &amp;amp; all their key binds.
I skim through describe-mode the first time I am using a mode. The functions are generally named as namespace-like-action-like-something-else. I remember the pattern so I can type out these functions with some autocompletion engine2.</description></item><item><title>Why I like Smalltalk - Part 2 of 100 - Intention revealing names</title><link>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/why-i-like-smalltalk-part-2-of-100-intention-revealing-names/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/why-i-like-smalltalk-part-2-of-100-intention-revealing-names/</guid><description>Why I like Smalltalk: Part 2 of 100 - Intention revealing names1 🔗A properly named message communicates well. The developer does not have to look for the implementation. This has more to do with design, but it has been in Smalltalk&amp;rsquo;s genes since its inception.
What is an intention-revealing method? A message which
Reveals intention Hides implementation Gives return type hint Intention revealing names answer what instead of how.</description></item><item><title>My Editor Journey Till Now</title><link>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/my-editor-journey-till-now/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/my-editor-journey-till-now/</guid><description>My Editor Journey Till Now 🔗What did I start with? 🔗2018
My first editor was Emacs1. Why did I choose emacs? I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to exit Vim2.
I got really into programming with Scheme3. And I liked it so much I decided to choose the editor with its roots in it.
Learning emacs was just getting comfortable with its keybinds. The power of emacs comes from extensibility. Although I am a casual lisp programmer, I never bothered to learn elisp and extend emacs to my liking.</description></item><item><title>Why I like Smalltalk - Part 1 of 100 - Documentation</title><link>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/why-i-like-smalltalk-part-1-of-100-documentation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://surajyadav.xyz/posts/why-i-like-smalltalk-part-1-of-100-documentation/</guid><description>Why I like Smalltalk: Part 1 of 100 - Documentation 🔗Smalltalk Documentation follows CRC1(Class, Responsibilities &amp;amp; Collaborators) 🔗 For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know what CRC is, it&amp;rsquo;s a tool that helps design objects. A CRC card consists of Class name at the top, responsibilities on the left side &amp;amp; collaborators on the right. Since a card models only one object, it enables rapid prototyping. It is feasible to go through many iterations before settling on an implementation.</description></item></channel></rss>